

Skills:

- JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, npm, Git;
- HTML5/CSS, MaterialUI, TailwindCSS;
- Figma;
- Vercel;

Languages:

Russian (Native)
English (High Proficiency)
Swedish (Intermediate)

Hobbies

Photography, coding, design & visual arts; hiking & camping, cycling & running;

Maria Pokryshkina

mariapokryshkina@gmail.com

+358453262363

Profile

A Junior Front-End Developer with entry-level experience specializing in web-development and user interface design. A passionate soul with an eye for detail and desire to learn and grow in a collaborative environment. Excelling at creating personalized designed web solutions and implementing them using React.js.

Experience

SENIOR REPAIR SPECIALIST

Helsinki Swappie Oy | March 2021- Present

FRONT-END DEVELOPER TRAINEE

Helsinki Tira | August 2022 -November 2022 Phone investigation & repair; Welding; Blancco, 3UTools & Hemuli; Panic logs analysis; Internal guidance and workshops; Stocktaking;

Development and implementation of Tira.so (digital workspace) app using HTML5,CSS, React.js (developing pages, page elements, coding & debugging); Creating responsive designs, building wireframes & developing prototypes; Participating in daily scrum meetings & team collaboration; Using source control tools (GitHub) & deployment platforms (Vercel);

SALESPERSON

Helsinki Trumpbell Oy February 2018 - March 2020

SCIENTIFIC RESEARCH DEPARTMENT SPECIALIST

Petrozavodsk PetrSu|September 2015 -July 2016 Direct sales; Customer consulting & communication; Returns & complaints; Stocking merchandise and creating displays; Sales optimisation & promotions;

Cross-department communication & formal correspondence; Documentation records; Translation of documents and academic articles; Working with academic databases; Negotiations; Resource planning & organisational matters;

Education

HELSINKI BUSINESS COLLEGE

Full-Stack Web Developer

Helsinki August 2021 - December 2022 HTML5 and CSS3; UI / UX Design and Prototyping(Figma); Programming JavaScript; Typescript; Data structures; React & Redux; Node & Express; Unit Testing & Quality Assurance; Continuous Integrations and AWS; Working in a Software Development Team; Software Development Project (in collaboration with PHZ Full Stack);

ÅBO AKADEMI UNIVERSITY

Master of Economics and Business Administration - MBA

Turku August 2016 - May 2020 Information & Knowledge Management; Information Architecture; Competitive Intelligence; Information Management; Information Strategies; Sustainable Business; Intercultural Marketing Management; Management on Industrial Brands; Business Analytics; Project Management; Financial Economics;

Projects

Software Development Project in collaboration with PHZ Full-Stack

Helsinki March2022 - May 2022

In this project our team collaborates with PHZ Full-Stack in order to create a NPS (Net Promoter Score) application. Such application enables users to use the dashboard for creating their own surveys which could be further integrated into any web-platform. An app is created using React.js, Material UI. Tasks are communicated through Trello, while code is shared and maintained via GitHub.

Links

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maria-pokryshkina0251214b/

GitHub: https://github.com/mariapokryshkina

Personal Portfolio Page: https://personal-portfolio-tawny-

alpha.vercel.app